第一口语网
www.1speaking.com
看英语电影学习英语是一种非常好的方法
但需要掌握正确的方法，才能获得更好的效果
首先看带有中英对照字幕的来辅助学习
其次再看只带英文字幕的来练习
如果发现听不懂或感到有些吃力
可以再看中英对照字幕的来加深学习
就这样中英文、英文字幕的反复多次的学和练
很快就能轻松的听懂
听得多了，输入大脑的语言信息也就多了。
嘴自然就能说出来了，这就是自然学习法。
而且是一种轻松愉快，乐此不疲的好方法。
为了帮助大家更好更快捷的学习英语
第一口语网特别制作了带有中英、英文字幕的影视
以满足大家专门学习英语的需求
此外，还可以选择《跟我练口语》系列视频来集中强化练习
因为《跟我练口语》内的视频都是经过精选的电影片段
而且还是按照场景进行了详细的分类
可以将庞大复杂的英语化整为零
为我们有选择的来各个突破提供了方便
用到什么就学什么，为用而学
不用或暂时不用的，可以先不去学
这就大大减少了学习的工作量
可以把精力用到重点上，效果立竿见影
这才是看影视学习英语最有效的好方法
此片仅为学习英语之用
禁止做任何商业用途
I love that restaurant.
我最喜欢那餐厅。
I heard Madonna went into labor there.
我听说麦当娜在那里工作。
Oh, gosh! I have to go shopping.
哦, 上帝, 我得去购物了。
Ok. I'll see you tonight. Bye.
好了，我们晚上见，再见。
Bruiser, what's this?
拳师，这是什么？
Ah! good luck tonight. Elle and Warner forever.
啊！祝今晚好运，埃尔和沃纳永结同心。
Oh, that's so cute.
噢，这是太可爱了。
Oh, my gosh! You guys are so sweet!
噢，老天，你们俩个真好！
But I'm not positive it'll happen tonight.
但我不肯定那事今晚会发生。
Hello! He just had lunch with his grandmother.
嘿！他刚和奶奶吃过午餐。
You know he got the rock.
你知道他拿到了钻石。
Why else would she have flown in from Newport?
为什么她会从纽波特飞过来？
it's not like she'd Fed Ex a six-carat diamond.
她不会叫空运公司运送一颗六克拉的钻石吧。
Do you really think?
你真的这么想？
I can't believe you're getting engaged!
我不敢相信你们就要订婚了！
Oh, my gosh...
噢，天呀...
you guys have to help me pick out the perfect outfit.
你们俩得帮我桃选合适的衣服。
Come on!
来吧！
I think you should go with the red.
我认为你应该穿红色。
it's the color of confidence.
那是自信的颜色。
I don't understand why you're disregarding
我不明白为什么你那么漠视
your signature color.
你个性的颜色。
He's proposing. I can't look like I would on any other date.
他建议，我不能看着像个普通约会的打扮。
This is the date... the night I'll always remember.
这晚上的约会将令我终生难忘。
I want to look special.
我要看起来很特别。
Bridal.
像新娘
But not like I expect anything.
但还不像我希望的那样。
There's nothing I love more than a dumb blonde with daddy's plastic.
没有什么让我更喜欢的，一个用爸爸信用卡的愚蠢金发女郎。
Did you see this one? We just got it in yesterday.
你看看这件吗？我们昨天刚进的。
Is this low-viscosity rayon?
这是低黏性的人造丝吗？
Yes. Of course.
是的，当然。
With a half-loop top-stitching on the hem?
是用半孔布面缝针的吗？
Absolutely. it's one of a kind.
是的。就是那种类型的。
it's impossible to use a half-loop top-stitching
低黏性人造丝的布面是不可能
on low-viscosity rayon. It would snag the fabric.
用半孔缝针的，它会嵌入织物。
And you didn't just get it in.
并且你不是刚进的货。
I saw it in the June Vogue a year ago.
我一年前在6月的时尚杂志见过。
So if you're trying to sell it for full price
如果你想原价卖掉它
you picked the wrong girl.
你挑错了人。
Girls, this is it.
姑娘们，就是这件了。
In a few hours
几个小时后
I'll be the future Mrs. Warner Huntington lll.
我就是未来的沃纳亨廷顿三世太太。
Hello.
你好
Wow! You look so beautiful.
哇！你看上去太漂亮了。
So do you.
你也一样。
Let's get out of here.
我们出去吧。
Must be strange having such perfect eyes.
拥有那么完美的眼睛一定觉得很怪吧。
God, you're so wonderful. Elle, thank you.
上帝，你真漂亮。埃尔，谢谢你。
Here's to us.
这是祝我们的
To us.
祝我们
Elle. Yes.
埃尔。嗯。
One of the reasons I wanted to come here tonight was
我今晚来这的原因之一是
to discuss our future.
讨论一下我们的未来。
And I am fully amenable to that discussion.
我赞成这样做。
Good. You know how we've been having all kinds of fun lately. Ya.
好。你知道最近我们玩的很开心。是的。
Well, Harvard is gonna be different.
可是，哈佛会是不同的。
Law school is a completely different world
法学院是全然不同的世界
and I need to be serious. Of course.
我要认真一点。当然。
And my family expects a lot from me.
并且我的家人对我抱很大期望
Right. I expect a lot from me.
对。我对自己也有很大期望。
I plan on running for office someday.
我打算日后参选参议员。
I fully support that. You know that way.
我是完全支持你的，你知道那方法。
Absolutely. But the thing is...
绝对支持。但事情是...
if I'm going to be a senator by the time I'm thirty
假如我当上参议员要到30岁
I need to stop dicking around.
我不能再瞎闹了。
Warner, I completely agree.
沃纳，我完全同意。
That's why I think it's time for us...
那就是为什么我认为我们是时候...
Elle, pooh bear
埃尔，宝宝熊
Yes.
是的
I do.  I think we should break up.
我愿意。我认为我们该分手了。
What?
什么？
I've been thinking, and it's the right thing to do.
我一直在想，这样做是正确的。
You're breaking up with me?
你和我分手？
I thought you were proposing.
我还以为你要求婚
Proposing?
求婚？
Elle, if I'm going to be a senator
埃尔，如果我当上参议员
I need to marry a Jackie, not a Marilyn.
我要娶名媛，而不是玛丽莲（电影明星）。
So you're breaking up with me because I'm too blonde?
所以你是因我金发而和我分手？
No. That's not entirely true.
不，不完全是这样。
Then what? My boobs are too big?
那是什么？我胸脯太大？
Your boobs are fine.
埃尔，你的胸脯很好。
So when you said that you would always love me
那么当你说你会永远爱我的时候
you were just dicking around?
你是闹着玩的吗？
Elle, I-I do love you.
埃尔，我，我是爱你。
I-I-I just can't marry you.
我，我，我只是不能娶你。
You have no idea of the pressure that I am under.
我没有办法因为我有压力。
My family has five generations of senators.
我家五代是参议员。
My brother's in the top three at Yale Law.
我哥哥在耶鲁法学院是前三名。
He just got engaged to a Vanderbilt, for Christ's sake.
他刚跟一个范德比尔特家族的人订婚了。
Bad salad!
糟糕的沙拉!
Sweetie
亲爱的
Pooh bear?
宝宝熊？
it's not like I have a choice here, sweetheart!
我是逼于无奈的!
You get the car, I'll get the check.
你去拿车吧，我来结帐。
I won't be having the salad.
我不吃沙拉。
Come on. Let me take you home.
来吧，让我送你回家吧。
No. Elle, believe me. I never expected to do this...
不。埃尔，相信我。我从没想这样做...
but I think it's the right thing.
但我认为这是对的。
How can it be the right thing when we're not together?
我们不在一起又怎么是对的？
While I have to think of my future
我得考虑前途
and what my family expects of me.
和我家人对我的期望。
So you're breaking up with me
所以你甩掉我
because you're afraid your family won't like me?
是因为你怕你的家人不喜欢我？
Everybody likes me.
每个人都喜欢我。
East Coast people are different.
东岸的人是不同的。
Because I'm not a Vanderbilt, suddenly I'm white trash?
我不是名门望族，就是垃圾吗？
I grew up in Bel Air! Across the street from Aaron Spelling!
我自小就与电视监制之王为邻!
I think most people would agree that's a lot better
我想更多的人会认同这样更好
than some stinky old Vanderbilt!
比起那讨厌的范德比尔特家族！
I told you. I need someone serious.
我告诉过你，我要认真的找对象。
But I'm seriously in love with you.
但我是认真爱你的。
Isn't that enough?
这还不够吗？
Pooh bear, just get in the car.
宝宝熊，上车吧。
No.
不
You'll get ruin your shoes.
你会毁掉你的鞋子。
Ok.
好吧
Morning, Amy.
早上好，埃米。
Elle, it's Amy.
埃尔，我是埃米。
I'm having trouble with this whole lip-liner thing.
我用唇线笔有点麻烦。
Sweetie, didn't you hear? Hear what?
亲爱的，你没听说吗？听说什么？
it's terrible. He dumped her.
很可怕，他甩了她。
Why me?
我为什么？
Because you're not gonna remember anything after tonight.
因为今晚之后，你什么都记不起来了。
Oh, you're wrong.
噢，你错了。
I will remember, no matter what.
我会记得，不管怎样。
And I'm never gonna lose you again.
我也永远不会再失去你。
You couldn't.
你不会的
You're a part of me.
你是我的一部分
I love you.
我爱你
Liar!
骗子！
Honey, you have to leave this room.
心爱的，你得离开这个房间了。
it's been, like, a week.
已一个星期了。
So? Drink this.
那又怎样？喝了这个。
What always makes us feel better no matter what?
有什么总会令我们感觉好点，不管是什么？
修手指甲和脚指甲
She had eight grilled cheese sandwiches.
她吃了八客烤干酪三明治。
She stuffed them in her mouth all at once.
全部一起往嘴里塞。
It was so sad.
真是太伤心了。
We thought she'd be the first to walk down the aisle...
我们以为她将是第一个结婚的...
and now she's totally adrift.
现在她没着落了。
Totally.
没错
She hasn't conditioned her hair in a week.
她一星期没用护理过头发了。
Maybe she's going for the grunge look.
也许她要变成邋遢的形象。
And her nails are full-on chipped.
她的指甲油颜色剥落了。
So trailer park.
很低俗
Oh, my God! Do you know who this is?
噢，老天！你知道这是谁吗？
No. That's Warner's older brother! Who?
不认识。那是沃纳的大哥！谁？
Third year Yale Law student Putnam Bowes Huntington lll
耶鲁大学法律系三年级生帕特南亨廷顿三世
and his fiancee Layne Walker Vanderbilt
和他的未婚妻比莱恩沃克范德比尔特
first year Yale Law.
耶鲁法学院一年级生。
This is the type of girl that Warner wants to marry!
沃纳要娶的是她这样的女孩！
This is what I need to become to be serious!
我要变得成她这样才算认真！
What? Practically deformed?
怎么样？丑得畸型？
No. A law student.
不。一个法律系学生。
Elle.
埃尔。
Law school?
法学院？
it's a perfectly respectable place, daddy.
那是非常高尚的地方，爸爸。
Honey, you were first runner up at the Miss Hawaiian Tropics contest.
乖女儿，你是夏威夷小姐亚军
Why are you gonna throw that all away?
为什么你要全放弃呢？
Going to Harvard is the only way I'll get the love of my life back.
去哈佛是我挽回爱情的唯一办法。
Sweetheart, you don't need law school.
亲爱的，你不用念法学院。
Law school is for people who are boring and ugly and serious.
法学院只适合沉闷、丑陋和严肃的人。
And you, Button, are none of those things.
而你完全不是这样的人。
Harvard Law School?
哈佛法学院？
That's right.
是的
But that's a top three school.
但那是三所顶尖大学之一。
Oh, I have a 4.0.
噢。我拿了4分。
Yes, but your major is fashion merchandising.
对，但你主修的是时装营销
Harvard won't be impressed that you aced History of Polka Dots.
哈佛不会感兴趣你擅长圆点花纹的历史。
What are your back-ups?
你有什么后备的？
I don't need back-ups. I'm going to Harvard.
我才不需要。我要去哈佛。
Well, then, you'll need excellent recommendations from your professors.
那好吧，你需要教授的高度推荐。
Ok. And a heck of an admissions essay.
好的。以及一份极好的入学论文。
And at least a 175 on your LSATs.
还有，法学院入学公开考试最少要有175分。
I once had to judge a tighty-whitey contest for Lambda Kappa Pi.
我曾当贴身白衣比赛评判。
Trust me, I can handle anything.
相信我，我什么都能应付。
Thank you!
谢谢你！
You're welcome.
不客气
Because I have a metrabolism...
因为我有心陈代谢作用...
I have a really high metrab... it's metabol...
我有极高的心陈代谢作用...是新陈代...
Oh! my God!
噢！天啊！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Reading about the LSATs.
在读有关LSAT的书。
My cousin had that.
我表妹曾有这个病。
Apparently, you get a really bad rash on your... Oh.
看来，你真的长了皮疹... 噢。
The LSATs are an exam.
这“LSATs”是个考试。
Girls, I'm going to Harvard!
姑娘们，我打算去哈佛！
You mean like on vay-kay? Let's all go!
去度假吗？我们都去！
Road trip!
上路旅行！
No. I'm going to Harvard Law School.
不，我要上哈佛法学院。
Why?
为什么？
Elle, now, I know you're upset about all this,
埃尔，现在，我知道这一切让你很烦恼，
but can't you just take a Percoset?
但你不能吃药片吗？
Ok, once Warner sees me as a serious law student...
好的，一旦沃纳看到我成了认真的法学院学生...
he'll totally want me back.
他绝对会再要我。
it's a completely brilliant plan!
这是个十分英明的计划！
But isn't it hard to get into law school?
但是进入法学院容易吗？
I had the highest GPA in Delta Nu.
我的平均分数是全女生会最高。
Oh, well. Here, you're gonna need this.
噢，好的。给，你一定需要这个。
Your scrunchy?
你的头饰？
My lucky scrunchy. it helped me pass Spanish.
我的幸运头饰，它帮我考过西班牙文。
You passed Spanish because you gave Professor Montoya
你通过西班牙文是因为你对蒙托亚教授
a lap dance after the final.
大献殷勤。
Yeah. luckily.
是的，很幸运。
埃尔伍兹哈佛录影带论文
Hi, my name is Elle Woods, and for my admissions essay.
你好，我的名字叫埃尔伍兹，这是我的入学论文。
I'm gonna tell all of you at Harvard.
我要告诉哈佛的所有人。
why I'm gonna make an amazing lawyer.
为什么我会成为出色的律师。
As president of my sorority
作为女生会主席
I'm skilled at commanding the attention of a room
我擅长观察房间
and discussing very important issues.
和讨论很重要的问题。
it has come to my attention that the maintenance staff
我已经注意到了维修人员
is switching our toilet paper from Charmin to generic.
将卫生纸由原来的名品牌改为一般货色。
All those opposed to chafing please say“aye”.
所有反对的请说“是”
aye.
是
A: neither type of opera or neither type of rap is on sale.
A：歌剧或是饶舌歌都没有出售。
B: neither type of jazz and neither type of opera is on sale.
B：爵士乐或歌剧都没有出售。
C: neither type of opera and neither type of soul...
C：歌剧或灵歌都没...
Party! Delta Nu, we love you!
开派对！奴江三角洲，我们爱你！
Hey.
嘿
Ok.
好吧
I'm able to recall hundreds of important details at the drop of a hat.
在一顶帽子掉下的瞬间，我能够回忆起数百个重要的细节。
Hey, Elle, do you know what happened on Days of Our Lives yesterday?
嘿，埃尔，你知道昨天“青葱岁月”剧集的剧情发展吗？
Why, yes, Margot, I do.
嗯，是的，玛戈，我知道。
Once again, we join Hope in the search for her identity.
霍普在寻找她的身份。
As you know, she's been brainwashed by the evil Stefano.
因为你知道，她被邪恶的斯蒂芬诺洗脑了。
Wait, get set and go!
等下，准备，开始！
And eight, seven...
还有，八、七...
总分：143
One forty-three.
143分
I feel comfortable using legal jargon in everyday life.
我感觉在日常生活中使用法律术语很自如。
I object!
我不以为然！
法学院入学公开试　第一至六段
it's here!
送来了！
Elle. What? it's here!
埃尔。什么？送来了！
The LSAT scores! it's here!
入学考试成绩！在这儿！
Open the scores!
打开成绩单！
What's the score?
分数是多少？
One seventy-nine!
179分
And that's why you should vote for me.
因此这就是为什么你们该投票于我。
Elle Woods, future lawyer for the class of 2004.
埃尔伍兹，未来2004班级的律师。
She does have a 4.0 from CULA
她在加州洛杉矶大学拿了满分
and she got a 179 on her LSATs.
并且入学公开试拿了179分。
A fashion major?
主修时装？
Well, sir, we've never had one before
是的，先生。我们以前从来没有过
and aren't we always looking for diversity?
并且我们不是总要多元化吗？
Her list of extracurricular activities is impressive.
她的课外活动令人印象深刻。
She was in a Ricky Martin video.
她在瑞奇马汀的录影带出现过。
Clearly, she's interested in music.
很明显，她对音乐感兴趣。
She also designed a line of fauxfur panties
她也设计了一系列仿皮裘内裤
for her sorority's charity project.
是为了女生会的慈善活动。
She's a friend to the animals as well as a philanthropist.
她对动物很友善，就像慈善家一样。
Elle Woods
埃尔伍兹
welcome to Harvard.
欢迎到哈佛来。
Bruiser, it's so exciting! Look! Harvard!
拳师，真是令人兴奋，看！哈佛！
Are you excited?
你激动吗？
哈佛法学院伟恩楼
This is our new house for the next three years.
在未来的三年里这就是我们的新家了。
Oh! Are you thirsty?
噢！你口渴了吗？
Ok. Let's get you some water.
好吧，我给你倒点水。
Sweetheart, you just look parched.
宝贝，你看上去渴坏了吧。
Hey, Brad, check out Malibu Barbie!
嘿，布拉德，出来看看马利布巴比娃娃！
Where's the beach, honey?
沙滩在哪儿呢？
Here you go.
喝吧
Good boy. Warner's gonna be so excited to see you.
好小子，沃纳看见你会很高兴。
Guys, this way.
各位，这边来。
This ain't L.A.! Come on, Bruiser.
这儿不是洛杉矶！来吧，拳师。
Check her out! Look at the way she walks!
看看她! 看她走路的样子!
it's gonna be so exciting.
令人兴奋
Now, don't be scared. Everyone will love you.
现在，不要害怕，每个人都会喜欢你的。
欢迎2004年度法学院学生
Hi. Woods, comma, Elle.
你好，我姓伍兹，叫埃尔。
Class schedule, map, book list.
上课时间表、地图、书本清单。
Wait a second. My social events calendar is missing.
等一下，我的社交运动日程表不见了。
Your what?
你的什么？
Social events... you know, mixers, formals
社交活动...你知道的，联谊会、正式聚会
clambakes, trips to the Cape.
野餐会、旅行。
Ok. Has Warner Huntington lll checked in yet?
好吧。沃纳亨廷顿三世报到了没有？
Um, no.
嗯，没有。
Maybe you should check with the cruise director on the Lido deck.
也许你应该向露天泳池的导游总监查询吧。
Ok, welcome to law school.
好的，欢迎到来法学院。
This is the part where we go around in a circle
这部分是我们转圈依次
and everyone says a little bit about themselves.
每个人自我介绍一下。
Let's start with you.
让我们你先开始吧。
Um, my name is David Kidney.
我的名字叫大卫基尼。
I have a masters in Russian literature
我有一个俄国文学硕士学位
a PhD in biochemistry and
一个生物化学博士学位
for the last eighteen months
在过去的18个月里
I've been deworming orphans in Somalia.
在索马利亚给孤儿除虫
Awesome. What about you?
好极了，你呢？
Hey. How you doing? I'm Enid Wexler.
嘿，你们怎么样？我是伊妮德伟斯勒。
I got a Ph.D. from Berkeley in women's studies
我拿到妇女研究博士学位
emphasis in the history of combat
主攻女权运动抗争史
and last year, I single-handedly organized
去年，我筹组支持女同性恋
the march for Lesbians Against Drunk Driving.
反醉酒驾驶游行
Killer. Thanks. Good times.
厉害。谢谢，很开心。
Aaron Mitchell.
阿伦米切。
I graduated first in my class from Princeton.
我以班级第一名毕业于普林斯顿。
I have an l.Q. of 187...
我智商是187
and it's been suggested that Stephen Hawking stole his Brief History of Time
霍京的“时间短史”可能抄袭
from my fourth grade paper.
我四年级的作业
Cool!
酷!
Me? Yeah.
我吗？是的。
Ok. Hi. I'm Elle Woods and this is Bruiser Woods
好的。你们好，我是伍兹埃尔，这是拳师伍兹
and we're both Gemini vegetarians.
我们都是双子座的素食者。
I have a bachelor's degree in fashion merchandising...
我有一个加州洛杉矶大学时装销售规划的学士学位
from CULA, and I was a Zeta Lambda Nu sweetheart
获选为男生会之甜心
president of my sorority, Delta Nu
是女生会主席
and last year, I was homecoming queen.
去年我是同学会皇后。
Oh, two weeks ago I saw Cameron Diaz at Fred Segal
两个星期前我在时装店遇上女星卡麦蓉狄亚
and I talked her out of buying this truly heinous angora sweater.
说服她不要买那令人憎恶的兔毛毛衣。
Whoever said orange was the new pink was seriously disturbed.
谁说橙色是新的粉红色就是神智失常。
Wish me luck, Bruiser.
祝我好运吧，拳师。
This is my first class as a serious law student.
这是我做为一个认真的法律系学生的第一堂课。
I totally look the part.
我完全像个法学院学生。
Elle?
埃尔？
Warner?
沃纳？
I totally forgot you go here.
我完全忘了你在这儿上课。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I'm sorry. Are you here to see me?
对不起，你是来这儿见我的吗？
No, silly. I go here.
不，笨蛋，我从这儿过。
You go where?
你去哪儿？
Harvard. Law school.
哈佛法学院
You got into Harvard Law?
你考入哈佛法学院？
What, like it's hard?
怎么了？好像很难吗？
Oh, my gosh, Warner, it'll be so great.
噢，我的天，沃纳，这将会很伟大。
I'm planning this great mixer. You have to help me.
我正筹备联谊会派对，你一定要帮我。
I'm thinking like a luau or casino night.
我正在想搞个夏威夷式宴会或是赌场之夜。
it'll be just like senior year except funner.
会像是四年级那样，但更好玩。
Oh, time to go. I have to go to class
哦，我该走了，我得去上课
but meet me after on the benches.
下课后在长椅见吧。
All right, bye!
好的，再见!
A legal education means you will learn to speak in a new language.
修读法律意味你们会学会说新的语言。
You will be taught to achieve insight into the world around you
你们会受训对身边的世界有洞察力
and to sharply question what you know.
并尖锐地质疑你们所知道的事。
The seat you have picked will be yours
你们所选的坐位
for the next nine months of your life.
在未来九个月都会坐同一位置。
And those of you in the front row
并且那些坐在前排的
beware.
小心了
The law is reason free from passion.
法律是没理由动感情的。
Does anyone know who spoke those immortal words?
有谁知道是谁说得这不朽的名句？
Who say it? Aristotle.
谁说的? 亚里士多德。
Are you sure?
你肯定吗？
Yes. Would you be willing to stake your life for it?
是的。你愿以生命作赌注吗？
I think so.
我认为可以。
What about his life?
他的性命呢？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Well, I recommend knowing before speaking.
好了，我建议知道了再说。
The law leaves much room for interpretation
法律留有诠释的空间
but very little for self-doubt.
但容不下自我怀疑。
And you were right.
还有你说的对。
It was Aristotle.
是亚里士多德说的
Now, I assume all of you have read pages 1-48
现在，我想你们都读过第1至48页
and are now well-versed in subject matter jurisdiction.
而且对主要案情裁判很熟识了。
Who can tell us about Gordon vs. Steele?
谁能告诉我们关于戈登对斯蒂尔的案例？
Let's call on someone from the hot zone.
让我们从好位置叫一个人。
Elle Woods?
埃尔伍兹?
Actually, I wasn't aware that we had an assignment.
其实，我不知道我们有作业
Well.
很好
Vivian Kensington.
维维安肯辛顿
Do you think it's acceptable that Ms. Woods is not prepared?
你认为是否可以接受伍兹小姐没有做好准备吗？
No.
不
I don't.
我不接受
Would you support my decision to ask her to leave class
你支持我决定请她离开教室
and to return only when she is prepared?
并当她准备好之后再回来？
Absolutely.
完全支持
Now, Ms. Kensington...
现在，肯辛顿小姐
did diversity jurisdiction exist in this case?
这个案例中存在裁判差异吗？
No, it did not.
不，并不存在。
Good. How about in the case of Owens vs. McCullough?
很好。欧文斯与麦卡洛的案例如何？
Excuse me. Are you OK?
请问，你没事吧？
Do they put you on the spot like that all the time?
他们总是这样令人难堪的吗？
The professors? They tend to do that. Socratic method.
教授们吗？他们都用苏格拉底的方式发问。
And so, If you don't know the answers, they just kick you out?
既然这样，是否不知道答案他们就会赶你出来呢？
You have Strom well, huh?
你上斯特龙威尔的课，是吗？
Yes! Did she do that to you, too?
是的! 她也有这样对你吗？
No. But she did make me cry once.
不，但她让我哭过一次。
Not in class. I waited till I got back to my room
不让进教室。我回宿舍前一直等着
but she'll kick you right in the ball... Or wherever, you know.
她会踢你的睾... 或是无论何处，你知道的。
She's really tough.
她真是很凶
Oh. Great.
哦，好极了
Don't worry, it gets better. Who else do you have?
别担心，情况会好转。你还修谁的课？
I have Callahan, Royalton, and Levinthal.
我有卡拉汉、罗亚顿和利文索尔的课。
Let's see, speak up in Callahan's class.
让我想想，在卡拉汉的课堂上要大胆发言。
He really likes people that are opinionated. OK.
他很喜欢有主见的人。好的。
And in Royalton's class try to get a seat in the back.
在罗亚顿的堂上，要坐在后排的座位。
He spits when he talks about products liability.
他谈货物负债时会口沫横飞。
And for Levinthal, make sure you read the footnotes.
至于利文索尔，你要读那些注脚。
That's where he gets a lot of his exam questions.
他考试时会在那儿出题。
Right.
对的
Wow. I'm really glad I met you.
哇。我真的很高兴认识你。
Are you a third year?
你是三年级吗？
Well... Elle.
嗯... 艾尔。
Hi! Thanks for all your help.
嘿！谢谢你的帮助。
Good luck.
祝好运
Hi, Warner.
你好，沃纳
Hi, uh. So...
你好，啊。那么...
how was your first class?
你上第一堂课怎么样？
Oh. It was good, except for this horrible preppy girl
噢。还好，只是这面目可憎的女孩
who made me look bad in front of the professor.
令我在教授面前难堪。
But no biggie.
没大不了
You're here now. So, how was your summer?
现在你来了。那么，你的暑假怎样？
Good. Uh, It was good.
不错，哦，挺好。
Did you do anything exciting?
有做刺激的事吗？
Uh... Hey! Have you met Vivian?
哦... 嘿！你见过维维安没有？
Oh, hi. Vivian Kensington.
噢，你好。我是维维安肯辛顿。
Do you know her?
你认识她？
She's... I'm his fiancee.
她是... 我是他的未婚妻。
Uh, I'm sorry. I just hallucinated. What?
啊，抱歉，我刚有个幻觉。什么？
Yeah. She-she was my girlfriend in prep school.
是的。她，她是我在初中的女朋友。
And, well, we got back together this summer
并且，嗯，我们今年夏天再次走到一起
at my grandmother's birthday party.
在我奶奶的生日聚会上。
Warner told me all about you.
沃纳告诉了我所有关于你的事。
You're famous at our club.
你在我们的俱乐部很有名。
But he didn't tell me you'd be here.
但他没说你会来这儿。
Pooh bear, I didn't know she would be here.
宝宝熊，我不知道她会来这儿。
Excuse me.
失陪了
美丽阁
理发和修甲
Oh, thank God!
噢，谢天谢地！
Are you free? it's an emergency.
你有空吗？是急事。
Bad day?
今天不开心？
You can't even imagine.
你无法想像
Spill.
说吧
Oh! I worked so hard to get into law school.
哦！我千辛万苦进法学院
I blew off Greek week to study for the LSATs.
我放弃参加希腊周为了入学公开试儿学习
I even hired a Coppola to direct my admissions video.
我雇了柯波拉执导我的入学录影带。
All to get my boyfriend Warner back.
这全都是为了挽回我的男朋友沃纳。
And now he's engaged to this awful girl Vivian
而现在他跟那个讨厌的维维安订婚了
so it was all for nothing, and I-I just wish...
因此一切努力都白费了，我，我只希望...
I just wish I had never gone to Harvard.
我只希望我从没有进过哈佛。
After you went to all that trouble.
你花了这么多心思
He's engaged!
他订了婚！
She's got the six-carat Harry Winston on her bony, unpolished finger.
她那只皮包骨，没涂指甲油的手，戴着那只六克拉的名牌钻戒。
What am I supposed to do?
我该怎么办呢？
You're asking the wrong girl.
你找错对象了
I mean, I'm with my guy eight years
我意思是，我和我的男人一起八年
and then one day, “I met someone else. Move out.”
有一天他说:“我有新欢了，搬出去”
Oh, no. That's awful.
噢，不是吧，真可怕。
Dewey kept the trailer and my precious baby Rufus.
杜威要了我的拖车及我的宝贝鲁佛斯。
I didn't even get to throw him a birthday party.
我甚至来不及为他举行生日聚会。
No. No? what's a girl to do?
不。不？那女人能怎么办呢？
He's a guy who followed his pecker to greener pastures.
他就是爱到处鬼混的人。
and I'm a middle-aged high-school dropout
而我人到中年，中学还没念完
who's got stretch marks and a fat ass.
皮肤松弛，还有个大屁股。
That's terrible.
那真是可怕
Yep. Happens every day.
对，每天都有发生。
So what's this Vivian got that you don't have?
那么这个维维安有什么东西是你没有的？
Three tits?
三个乳头？
She's from Connecticut.
她来自康乃狄格州
She belongs to his stupid country club.
她和他在同一乡村俱乐部。
Is she as pretty as you?
她像你那么漂亮吗？
She could use some mascara and some serious highlights
她要涂睫毛液和染发
but she's not completely unfortunate looking.
但她不是毫不漂亮。
Hello, ladies.
女士们
-Hey,there. -How you doing? Sign here.
Oh,jeez.
Look what I did.
-See you later. -Bye-bye, sugar.
Aw, shit.
Could I have been any more goddamn spastic?
it's OK.
Are you sure this Warner guy is, like, the one?
Definitely. I love him.
Well, if a girl like you can't hold on to her man...
then there sure as hell isn't any hope for the rest of us.
What are you waiting for?
Steal the bastard back.
I should warn you...
that in addition to competing against each other...
for the top grade in this class...
you will also be competing for one of my firm's...
highly coveted four internship spots next year...
where you will get to assist on actual cases.
Let he bloodbath begin.
Now, let's commence with our usual torture.
Ms. Woods...
would you rather have a client who committed a crime...
malum in se or malum prohibitum?
Neither.
And why is that?
I would rather have a client who's innocent.
Dare to dream, Ms. Woods.
Ms. Kensington, which would you prefer?
Malum prohibitum.
Because then the client would have committed...
a regulatory infraction as opposed to a dangerous crime.
Well done, Ms. Kensington.
You've obviously done your homework.
Now let us look at malum prohibitum...
a little more closely.
it has been said... Yes, Ms. Woods?
I changed my mind. I'd pick the dangerous one...
'cause I'm not afraid of a challenge.
Who is that?
Wow.
Guys.
-Can she play? -Hi!
Get outta here.
-Hi, everybody. -Elle, what are you doing here?
I've come to join your study group.
Look, I brought sustenance. Who's first?
Our group is full.
Is this like an RSVP thing?
No. it's like a smart people thing.
And as Viv said, we're full.
Come on, we can make room for one more.
We've already assigned the outlines.
The answer is no.
Oh, OK. I'll just leave, then.
Hey, maybe there's, like, a sorority...
you could, like, join instead, like?
If you had come to a rush party...
I would have at least been nice to you.
Is that before you voted against me...
and then called me a dyke behind my back?
I don't use that word.
You must have heard it from Vivian.
-Hello? -Hey, it's me.
it's Elle! Guess what I'm doing right this second!
I don't know. What?
I'm picking out my wedding dress!
-What? -Josh proposed!
Did you get the rock yet?
Almost.
Well, hurry up, so you can come home!
We miss you!
I miss you guys, too. The people here are so vile.
Hardly anybody speaks to me...
Oh, my God! I almost forgot to tell you!
What?
I got bangs! My hair is so now.
Really?
OK, so just listen to me.
Keep June 1 st open, you're one of my bridesmaids...
and give Warner our love...
because I'm getting married!
So don't forget. Eight o'clock at 45 Duns tn Street.
-it'll be a really nice party. -We'll be there.
And don't forget to bring your own merlot!
No way! Is somebody at this school actually having a party?
Yes...
But it's a costume party.
You probably wouldn't want to come.
I love costume parties.
Well, then I guess we'll see you there.
Oh, at 45 Duns ton Street.
Oh, my God!
Thanks for inviting me, girls. This party is super fun.
Nice outfit.
I like your outfit, too.
Except when I dress up as a frigid bitch...
I try not to look so constipated.
Oh, she's horrible.
You've got the ring, sweetie.
-Nice ears. -How you doing'?
Warner, the English language...
is all about subliminal domination.
Take the word semester.
A perfect example of this school's...
discriminatory preference of semen to ovaries.
That's why I'm petitioning to have next term...
be referred to as the winter ovester.
-Excuse me. Hey,Warner. -Wow!
Don't you look like a walking felony?
Thank you. You're so sweet.
Are you having fun?
I am now. What's with the costume?
I just decided to dress up.
Really.
I feel like we barely get to see each other...
since we've been here.
I know. I'm so busy with these case studies and hypos.
I know what you mean. I can't imagine doing...
all this and Callahan's internship next year.
That's gonna be so much.
Elle, come on, you'll never get the grades...
to qualify for one of those spots.
You're not smart enough, sweetie.
Wait, am I on glue...
or did we not get into the same law school?
Yeah, but...
But what? We took the same LSATs...
and we're taking the same classes.
I know, but come on, Elle, be serious.
You can do something more valuable with your time.
I'm never going to be good enough for you, am l?
-Oh, come on. -Just forget it!
I'll show you how valuable Elle Woods can be!
-Don't ask. -Wasn't gonna.
I love that sweater. it's Chanel.
Look.
Was she carrying books?
Thanks.
So,you've filed a claim.
What next?
Ms. Woods?
Don't you need to have evidence?
Meaning?
Meaning you need reasonable belief...
that your claim should have, like, evidenciary support?
And what kind of evidenciary support...
does this case require?
All sorts of things...
corrupt cops who are wheeling and dealing...
And the purpose of diminished capacity is?
To negate mens rea?
Are you ready?
Yes, you are!
Go. You can do this.
Listen to me, Dewey. You shut your mouth.
No, you shut your big mouth.
I'm doing all the talking.
What the hell do you want?
We're eating lunch.
I just thought that...
You just thought you could come here...
and show me what I'm definitely not missing?
That's not why I came by.
How many times you gonna come over here...
begging me to take you back, huh?
I was...
Dewey New combe?
Who's asking?
I'm Elle Woods. Miss Bonifante's attorney.
And I'm here to discuss the legal situation at hand.
Come again?
Do you understand what subject matter jurisdiction is?
-No.  I didn't think so.
Well, due to habeas corpus...
you and Miss Bonifante had a common law marriage...
which here to fore entitles her...
to what is legally referred to...
as equitable division of the assets.
Come again?
Due to the fact that you've retained this residence...
Miss Bonifante is entitled...
to full canine property ownership...
and will be enforcing said ownership right now.
Tell him, Paulette.
I'm taking the dog, dumbass!
That's awesome! We did it!
Come here.
Oh, my gosh, did you see him?
He's probably still scratching his head.
Which must be a nice vacation for his balls.
Thank you.
According to Swinney vs. Neubert...
Swinney,who was also a private sperm donor...
was allowed visitation rights as long as he came to terms...
with the hours set forth by the parents.
So, if we're sticking to past precedent...
Mr. Latimer wasn't stalking.
He was clearly within his rights to ask for visitation.
But Swinney was a one-time sperm donor...
and our defendant was an habitual sperm donor...
who also happens to be harassing the parents...
in his quest for visitation.
But without this man's sperm...
the child in question wouldn't exist.
Now you're thinking like a lawyer.
Yes, Ms. Woods?
Although Mr. Huntington makes an excellent point...
I have to wonder if the defendant...
kept a thorough record of every sperm emission...
made throughout his life.
interesting. Why do you ask?
Unless the defendant attempted to contact...
every single one-night stand to determine...
if a child resulted in those unions...
he has no parental claim over this child whatsoever.
Why now? Why this sperm?
I see your point.
And for that matter, all masturbatory emissions...
where his sperm was clearly not seeking an egg...
could be termed reckless abandonment.
I believe you've just won your case.
Ms. Woods, you did well today.
Really?
You're applying for my internship, aren't you?
I don't know.
You should. Do you have a resume?
Yes, I do.
Here it is.
it's pink.
And it's scented.
I think it gives it a little something extra.
See you next class.
Do you think she woke up one morning and said...
I think I'll go to law school today.
That lapse in judgment aside...
I think she's got a lot of potential.
Here's the Wind hamfile.
Smell this.
What's that?
it's her resume.
Smells good.
What's going on?
Callahan's firm is defending a murder trial.
His case load is so big, he's taking first year interns.
He picked them already?
My God, I can't believe it, Warner!
We got it!
That only leaves one for...
Me!
Yes!
Remember when we spent those four amazing hours...
in the hot tub after winter formal?
Yeah...No.
This is so much better than that!
Excuse me. I have some shopping to do.
Four hours?
You look very nice today, Vivian.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
We're defending Brooke Windham...
whose very wealthy husband was found shot to death...
in their Beacon Hill mansion.
Gold digger?
You'd think so since the stiff was 60...
but she was rich on her own.
Some kind of fitness empire.
You can buy her exercise tapes on infomercials.
Are you talking about Brooke Taylor?
Maiden name...Taylor.
You know her?
She's a Delta Nu!
She wasn't in my pledge class.
She graduated four years before me.
But I used to take her class at the Los Angeles Sports Club.
She's amazing!
Amazing? How?
She can make you lose three pounds in one class.
She's completely gifted.
in all likelihood, she's completely guilty.
She was seen standing over her husband's dead body.
By who?
His 26-year-old daughter and the pool boy.
Sorry, I'm late. Excuse me.
This is Emmett Richmond, another associate...
top three in his class...
and former editor of Harvard Law Review.
You've probably seen him...
lurking around campus doing my research.
Thanks for the introduction.
What about the murder weapon?
The gun is missing.
The coroner said he'd been dead 30 minutes...
when the cops arrived.
Giving Brooke plenty of time to stash it.
I just don't think Brooke could have done this.
Exercise gives you endorphins.
Endorphins make you happy.
Happy people don't shoot their husbands.
They just don't.
I didn't do it.
I walked in...
I saw my husband lying on the floor...
I bent down to check his heart, screamed my head off...
then Enrique and Chutney ran inside.
Your step-daughter and the pool boy came in...
where they saw you standing over the body...
covered in his blood.
Why would I kill my husband?
insurance, a love affair, pure unadulterated hatred.
The D.A. will come up with plenty of reasons.
I loved him.
He was 34 years older than you.
That doesn't look so good to a jury.
Then show them a picture of his dick.
That might clear a few things up.
Brooke, I believe you...
but a jury is going to want an alibi.
I can't give you that...
and if you put me on the stand, I'll lie.
Then I guess we're done for today.
I know you.
I'm a Delta Nu, and I'm a huge fan of yours.
You took my class in L.A.
You had the best high-kick I've ever seen.
Are you one of my lawyers?
Sort of.
Well, thank God one of you has a brain.
Let's go.
I'm the only one that believes her.
Callahan totally thinks she's guilty.
That's because men are big fat retards who don't...
Afternoon, ladies.
it's him.
Paulette Bonifante.
Oh, my God.
He's coming over here.
I've got a package.
He's got a package.
How you doing today?
Fine.
Take it easy.
See you later.
That's great, Paulette.
Is this the only interaction you two have ever had?
No. Sometimes I say OK instead of fine.
Why don't you offer him a cold beverage...
or a neck massage or something?
What's the point?
Trust me, Paulette. You have all the equipment...
you just need to read the manual.
Do you know what I'm saying?
I'll show you a little maneuver...
my mother taught me in junior high.
in my experience, it has a 98% success rate...
of getting a man's attention...
and when used appropriately...
it has an 83% rate of return on a dinner invitation.
Wow!
it's called the bend and snap.
Watch this.
Oh! I think I dropped something on the floor.
So you bend...and snap!
See?
Come on. You try it.
Bend...and snap!
OK...
a little less bend, a little more snap.
Like this?
Good snap.
Come on.
You! Come on, you can do it.
Bend...and snap.
Very, very good.
We can all do it!
-Come on, guys.  I can't do that.
You're gonna bend...
and snap!
Now put your head into it.
Bend...and snap!
Bend...and snap! Good job!
A little attitude, please.
Now, everybody smile. That's very important.
Pump! Pump! Pump!
Bend...and snap!
Good job, everybody!
Work it out! Work it out!
That's it! Wow!
Come on, Paulette!
Bend and snap!
Oh, my God! The bend and snap! Works every time!
If Brooke didn't kill the guy, then who did?
My money is on the angry daughter or the ex-wife.
Chutney has a trust fund.
She didn't need the insurance payoff or the inheritance.
What about the mother?
Covered. She was in Aspen at the time.
Vivian, get me some plum sauce.
Ten people saw her downing cosmopolitans...
at the Caribou Club.
All I know is it's not Brooke.
That's touching, but we need an alibi.
I brought you some necessities...
some Calvin Klein 720-count sheets...
the entire Clinique skin care line...
some aromatherapy candles, a loofah...
And the Bible.
You're an angel.
So how are you? Are you all right?
You look so...orange.
I'm just glad it's you and not Callahan.
He means well. He's very brilliant.
He better befor what I'm paying for him.
I have to tell you the real reason I came here.
Professor Callahan says we really need your alibi.
Elle, I can't.
You don't understand.
Who could understand better than me?
it's so shameful.
Whatever it is, Brooke, it could save you.
That's just it. It would ruin me.
How?
I've made my fortune on the ability...
to perfect women's bodies with Brooke's Butt-Buster workout.
You helped me go from a six to a four.
That's great!
On the day of Heyworth's murder...
I was getting...
What?
I was getting liposuction.
Liposuction!
Oh, God!
I know! I'm a fraud!
it's not like normal women can have this ass!
If my fans knew that I bought it...
I would lose everything!
I've already lost my husband.
I'd rather go to jail than lose my reputation.
Brooke... your secret's safe with me.
Thank you.
Vivian, grab me some coffee.
We got two interviews tomorrow...
that Gerard and Bobby will handle.
The ex-wife in an hour.
According to this communique from the prison...
our client apparently had a visit from her sister...
a Miss Delta Nu.
Anyone you know?
Yes. I went to visit her.
What the hell do you mean you went to visit her?
I went to get her alibi.
Did you get it?
it's really good.
Great. What is it?
I can't tell you.
Why the hell not?
Because I promised her I'd keep it a secret...
and I can't break the bonds of sisterhood.
Screw sisterhood! This is a murder trial...
not some scandal at the sorority house.
I want the alibi!
I can't give it to you...
but I can tell you she is innocent.
Mrs. Windham Vander mark is on line two for you.
Someone reason with her while I take this.
Are you crazy? Just tell him the alibi.
We'll lose this case if you don't.
Then we're not very good lawyers.
If you tell him, he'll probably hire you as a summer associate.
Who cares about Brooke? Think about yourself.
I gave her my word, Warner.
So what?
The ex-wife seems to be unconcerned...
with the fact that her interview is today.
She's at a spa in the Berkshires.
A spa? Isn't that like your mother ship?
I could go if you want me to.
Emmett? Go with her.
She seems completely untrustworthy to me.
Why?
This is a person who's made her living...
by telling women that they're too fat.
Brooke would never tell a woman she was too fat.
And she seems like she's hiding something.
Maybe it's not what you think.
Maybe it's exactly what I think.
You're really being a butthead.
A butthead?
Why would you call me that?
You need to have a little more faith in people.
You might be surprised.
I can't believe you called me a butthead.
No one's called me that since the ninth grade.
Maybe not to your face.
So this is what a spa looks like. Wow.
How do we find her?
I called ahead. She's in the mud room.
She's not naked, is she?
Mrs. Windham Vander mark?
So you found me.
We're from Austen, Platt, Jaret, and Callahan...
and we're here to ask you a few questions.
So I hear that little tart from California...
shot poor Heyworth.
That's what we're trying to prove didn't happen.
Do you have any reason to believe that it did?
I've never actually met the woman...
but my daughter tells me...
she can be quite the little bitch.
Did your daughter ever mention anything...
about the relationship between Brooke and Heyworth?
She did say that they humped like gorillas.
I guess it wasn't enough, though, for Brooke.
Why do you say that?
Well...
haven't you seen the cabana boy?
She's lying.
And you know this for a fact?
Did you see the icky brown color of her hair?
So? Now you discriminate against brunettes?
Why not? I'm discriminated against as a blonde.
Being a blonde is actually a pretty powerful thing.
You hold more cards than you think you do.
I personally would like to see you take that power...
and channel it towards the greater good.
Thanks. I'll see you tomorrow.
All right.
How do you think I'd look as a blonde?
I'm not sure you could handle it.
-Good night. -Bye.
So, I called your room last night.
I heard.
I was thinking maybe we could go out sometime.
No. You're a dork.
I'm in law school.
Look, I'm not going out with you.
I can't believe you'd even ask.
Girls like me don't go out with losers like you.
Let's get out of here.
Excuse me.
Why didn't you call me?
What?
We spent a beautiful night together...
and I never hear from you again?
I...
I'm sorry?
Sorry for what? For breaking my heart...
or for giving me the greatest pleasure...
I've ever known and then just taking it away?
Both?
Well, forget it.
I've spent too many hours crying over you.
So...when did you want to go out?
Come in.
Are you done with that deposition yet?
Yeah. Here, take it.
I've read it 20 times.
You know, Elle, I still can't believe...
you didn't tell Callahan the alibi.
it's not my alibi to tell.
I know.
And I thought that was very classy of you.
Really?
Sure.
Thanks.
Did you ever notice how Callahan never asks Warner...
to bring him his coffee?
He's asked me at least ten times.
Men are helpless. You know that.
I know. Warner doesn't even do his own laundry.
He has to have it sent out.
I know.
Did you know when he first applied...
he got wait-listed.
What?
His father had to make a call.
You're kidding.
No way!
God, that is such a precious dog.
His name is Bruiser. Do you want to hold him?
-He's very friendly. -Sure.
Look, he likes you.
He's giving me kisses.
Thanks, Jeff.
We're here today covering the trial of Brooke Windham.
She's charged with the murder of her husband...
Boston millionaire Heyworth Windham.
First to testify are the victim's daughter and ex-wife.
The Superior Court of Suffolk County is now in session.
The Honorable Judge Marina R. Bickford presiding.
You may be seated.
And where was she exactly?
Standing over my father's dead body.
And what was the defendant doing?
She was sitting next to the pool, topless...
while the Latin boy handed her a drink.
Mr. Salvatore, can you tell us what this is?
My uniform.
This is the uniform...
Mrs. Windham asked you to wear while cleaning her pool?
Are you having an affair with Brooke Windham?
Define affair.
Have you and Mrs. Windham had sexual relations?
Yes. OK? Yes.
Ladies and gentlemen, court will reconvene...
tomorrow morning at 9 A.M.
We're adjourned.
A Delta Nu would never sleep with a man who wears a thong.
Never!
I just liked watching him clean the filter.
I believe you, Brooke.
-Take care of me, Elle.  I will.
I got a big one for you.
Can you sign?
I got it.
You broke his nose?
I blew it, Elle.
My snap was all over the place.
I'll be there as soon as court is out.
We have to cross-examine Enrique.
But don't worry. My girlfriend Serena...
barfed on a guy during The Blair Witch Project...
and they ended up dating for three months.
Really? All right. Bye-bye.
OK. Bye.
Don't stomp your little last-season Prada shoes at me.
These aren't last season.
-He's gay! Enrique's gay! -What?
What kind of shoes are these?
Black ones.
-See! -What are you talking about?
He isn't Brooke's lover. He's making it up.
Back up. How do you know he's gay?
Gay men know designers. Straight men don't.
Know what?
He left a Chertape in the pool house one time.
While I appreciate your masterful legal theory...
I have a murder trial to attend to.
I'll take care of it. Thanks.
The court will come to order.
Mr. Salvatore, do you have any proof...
that you and Mrs. Windham were having an affair?
Only the love in my heart.
If that's all the proof that he has, Your Honor...
I think I'm done here.
You may step down.
I'd like to ask a couple of questions, Your Honor.
Just give me a couple minutes.
Did you ever take Mrs. Windham on a date?
-Yes. -Where?
A restaurant where no one could recognize us.
How long have you been sleeping with Mrs. Windham?
Three months.
-And your boyfriend's name is... -Chuck.
Silence!
Pardon me!
Yes, Mr. Salvatore?
I was confused.
I thought you said friend. Chuck is just a friend.
You bitch!
Chuck, wait!
Silence in my court! Sit down, Mr. Salvatore.
Silence in my courtroom!
How did I miss that? You were great.
Thanks.
-Good night. -Good night.
Callahan asked to see you before you leave.
Really?
He already has coffee, but maybe he needs a doughnut.
-Do you need any help? -No. I'm fine.
OK. Bye.
Come on in.
Sit down.
Is everything all right?
You followed your intuition today...
and you were right on target.
I should have listened.
Thank you.
About the alibi...
I'm sorry...
I'm impressed you took the initiative to go get it.
That's what makes a good lawyer.
On top of that, you gained the client's trust...
and kept it...that's what makes a great lawyer.
You're smart, Elle.
Smarter than most of the guys on my payroll.
Wow.
I think it's time to discuss your career path.
Have you thought about where you might be a summer associate?
Not really.
I know it's very competitive.
You know what competition's really about?
it's about ferocity, carnage.
Balancing human intelligence with animal diligence.
Knowing exactly what you want...
and how far you'll go to get it.
How far will Elle go?
Are you hitting on me?
You're a beautiful girl.
So everything you just said...
I'm a man who knows what he wants.
And I'm a law student who just realized...
her professor is a pathetic asshole.
Too bad. I thought you were a law student...
who wanted to be a lawyer!
You almost had me fooled.
What?
Maybe you should sleep with the jury, too.
Then we can win the case.
I'm quitting.
Why?
Law school was a mistake. This internship was a mistake.
What are you talking about? You earned it.
I didn't earn anything.
Callahan only gave me that internship...
because he liked the way I looked.
Which he made clear tonight when he tried to feel me up.
Callahan did what?
Just forget about it. I'm going back to L.A.
No more boring suits. No more pantyhose.
No more trying to be something that I'm just...
I'm just not.
What if you're trying to be somebody you are?
The hell with Callahan.
Stay.
Call me if you're ever in California.
What's the point in staying, Paulette?
All people see when they look at me...
is blond hair and big boobs.
No one's ever gonna take me seriously.
The people at law school don't. Warner doesn't.
I don't think my own parents take me seriously.
I just felt, like, for the first time...
that someone expected me to...
to do something more with my life...
than become a Victoria's Secret model.
But I was just kidding myself.
Callahan never saw me as a lawyer...
just as a piece of ass.
Just like everybody else.
Turns out I am a joke.
No, you're not a joke.
The hell with law school.
I just wanted to say good-bye.
If you're going to let one stupid prick ruin your life...
you're not the girl I thought you were.
Did you go in there knowing how to discredit Mr. Salvatore?
Absolutely.
it's a little thing I'd like to call strategy.
I had a feeling about Mr. Salvatore...
Is he always such an ass?
He's the top defense attorney in the state.
Of course he's an ass.
Fine. Is he an ass that'll win my case?
He's an ass that'll try.
He thinks I'm guilty.
That's not what's important.
If he doesn't trust me, why should I trust him?
Ask Elle. She looked pretty cozy with him last night.
You don't know what the hell you're talking about.
What's going on here?
-Elle quit. -What?
Callahan hit on her, so she quit.
My God. Scumbag.
-Oh, God. -What?
I feel terrible. I made a huge mistake.
Maybe there's something we can do about it.
Thank you.
What are you so happy about? You're on trial for murder.
Get up.
What?
You're fired. I have new representation.
Who?
Excuse you, you're in my way.
She's a law student. She can't defend you.
Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court ruling 3.03.
See? Thank you, David.
Counselors, approach the bench.
-You're not going up there. -Yes, I am.
Maybe you didn't hear me. You're fired.
Counselors, now. All of you.
Elle Woods, Your Honor.
Rule 3.03 of Supreme Judicial Court...
states that a law student may appear on behalf...
of a defendant in criminal proceedings.
Your Honor, I have no problem with this.
I do. I'm not allowing it.
But you agreed last night. in your office...
when we were discussing my career.
The ruling also states...
that you need a licensed attorney to supervise you.
-Mr. Callahan? -That I won't agree to.
I'll supervise, Your Honor.
Well, Ms. Woods, proceed.
Thank you,Your Honor.
Enjoy prison.
Mrs. Windham,you do realize what you're doing?
Absolutely.
Oh, my God! There she is!
We came to see your trial!
Look how cute. There's a judge and everything.
-And jury people. -Vote for Elle!
Ladies, take a seat.
Go, girl.
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth...
and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
I do. -Be seated.
Ms. Woods, you may begin your questioning.
First of all I would like to point out...
that not only is there no proof in this case...
but there is a complete lack of mens rea...
which by definition tells us there can be no crime...
without a vicious will.
I am aware of the meaning of mens rea.
What I'm unaware of...
is why you're giving me a vocabulary lesson...
when you should be questioning your witness.
Yes, Your Honor.
Miss Windham...
when you arrived back at the house...
was your father there?
Not that I saw, but like I said...
I went straight upstairs to take a shower.
And when you came downstairs, what happened?
I saw Brooke standing over his body...
drenched in his blood.
But Mrs. Windham didn't have a gun?
No. She'd stashed it by then.
Move to strike that from the record, Your Honor.
it's speculation. So stricken.
Go ahead.
Miss Windham, did you hear a shot fired?
No. I was in the shower.
So, sometime in the 20 minutes...
that you were in the shower, your father was shot.
I guess.
Your father was shot while you were in the shower...
but you didn't hear the shot because...
because you were in the shower?
I was washing my hair.
Where is she going with this?
Have a little faith, Gerard.
Miss Windham...
what had you done earlier that day?
I got up...
got a latte, went to the gym...
got a perm, and came home.
Where you got in the shower?
I believe the witness has made it clear...
that she was in the shower.
Yes, Your Honor.
Miss Windham, had you ever gotten a perm before?
How many would you say?
Two a year since I was 1 2.
You do the math.
A girl in my sorority, Tracy Marcinko, got a perm once.
We all tried to talk her out of it.
Curls weren't a good look for her.
She didn't have your bone structure.
But, thankfully, that same day...
she entered the Beta Delta Pi wett-shirt contest...
where she was completely hosed down from head to toe.
Objection! Why is this relevant?
I have a point, I promise.
Then make it.
Yes, ma'am.
Chutney, why were Tracy Marcinko's curls ruined...
when she got hosed down?
Because they got wet?
Exactly. isn't it the first cardinal rule...
of perm maintenance that you're forbidden to wet your hair...
for at least 24 hours after getting a perm...
at the risk of deactivating the ammonium thioglycolate?
And wouldn't somebody who's had, say,30 perms...
in their life be well aware of this rule?
And if in fact you weren't washing your hair...
as I suspect, because your curls are still intact...
wouldn't you have heard the gunshot?
And if in fact you had heard the gunshot...
Brooke Windham wouldn't have had time to hide the gun...
before you got downstairs...
which would mean you would have had to have found...
Mrs. Windham with a gun in her hand...
to make your story plausible. Isn't that right?
She's my age! Did she tell you that?
How would you feel if your father married someone your age?
You, however, had time to hide the gun...
after you shot your father.
I didn't mean to shoot him.
I thought it was you walking through the door!
Order! Order!
Order!
Oh, my God.
Bailiff, take the witness into custody...
where she will be charged for the murder of Heyworth Windham.
in the matter of The State vs. Brooke Windham...
this case is dismissed.
Mrs. Windham, you are free to go.
Thank you!
Elle, how did you know Chutney was lying?
Because she's brilliant, of course.
The rules of hair care are simple and finite.
Any Cosmo Girl would have known.
What?
I just wanted to say...
that you were so brilliant in there.
And that I was wrong.
And you are the girl for me.
Really?
Pooh bear...I love you.
I've waited so long to hear you say that.
But if I'm gonna be a partner at a law firm by the time I'm 30...
I need a boyfriend who's not such a complete bonehead.
Thank you, boys.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I present the graduates of Harvard Law School...
Class of 2004.
I am personally very honored to introduce...
this year's class-elected speaker.
After getting off to a quite interesting start...
here at Harvard...
she graduates today with an invitation to join...
one of Boston's most prestigious law firms.
I'm sure we are going to see great things from her.
Ladies and gentlemen, Elle Woods.
On our very first day at Harvard...
a very wise professor quoted Aristotle.
The law is reason free from passion.
Well, no offense to Aristotle...
but in my three years at Harvard...
I have come to find that passion is a key ingredient...
to the study and practice of law and of life.
it is with passion, courage of conviction...
and strong sense of self...
that we take our next steps into the world...
remembering that first impressions...
are not always correct...
you must always have faith in people...
and most importantly...
you must always have faith in yourself.
Congratulations, Class of 2004.
We did it!